# **Louis Schermerhorn**

I am an integrated marketing professional with 7 years of experience in digital marketing and account management. After leading campaign strategy for Broadway shows in NYC, I am returning to Chicago to pursue new opportunities.



908 377 3862 louis.schermerhorn@gmail.com in /louis-schermerhorn SKILLS Digital Marketing Presentation Media Planning Account Management Problem-Solving Research Communication Client Management Email Marketing Analytics Web Development Strategy

#### EXPERIENCE

SpotCo NYC 2015-2020

The world's leading entertainment advertising and branding agency. Behind some of the most iconic Broadway campaigns including Hamilton, Chicago, and Rent.

# Account Director (April 2018 - Present)

 Drove 32% growth in monthly sales by executing a fully integrated program for *Beetlejuice the Musical*, which included a new digital campaign, live events, a dedicated website, and social media activations.



- Led weekly client meetings, responding nimbly to shifts in the market and pivoting strategy if needed. Presented advertising opportunities, recommended strategy shifts and shared digital insights.
- Managed client annual budgets, including paid media, social media, broadcast production, fees, events and special promotions. Responsible for acquiring project estimates, updating as campaigns evolved, and actualizing with billing regularly.

#### Media Manager (September 2017 - March 2018)

- Planned, negotiated and executed fully integrated media campaigns for clients including digital, broadcast, print and outdoor. Presented these campaigns in client meetings and responded directly to producers and investors.
- Created and presented digital reports and insights to internal teams and clients. Sources included surveys, lift studies, raw campaign data and website analytics.
- Developed relationships with new media vendors and found opportunities for case studies, experiments and added value.
- Started podcast series "SpotCo Presents" to push the agency's content production.

#### Associate Digital Media Manager (July 2015 - August 2017)

- Executed digital campaigns in DoubleClick, Google AdWords, YouTube, Facebook, Instagram and Snapchat. Responsible for pixel implementation and maintenance.
- Shared insights with creative team in order to push the agency toward digital best practices, including vertical video, sequential ads and mobile-optimized messages.











CLIENTS INCLUDED

# Carol Fox & Associates

Chicago 2013-2015

An award-winning PR, branding, digital marketing and events agency based in Chicago and specializing in lifestyle, hospitality, arts, education and entertainment.

Account Executive (January 2015 - June 2015)

- Created marketing plans and timelines for performing arts clients, which included print, digital, broadcast and direct mail.
- Managed Google AdWords and Facebook advertising campaigns. Identified audiences, developed keywords, wrote copy and reported results.

Social Media and Marketing Assistant (June 2013 - December 2014)

• Wrote copy, managed content calendar, and ran giveaways and contests for social clients.

#### - EDUCATION

# **Northwestern University**

Evanston 2009-2013

Bachelor of Arts, School of Communication

- President and Executive Producer, The Dolphin Show (The Largest Student-Produced Musical in America), Marketing Director, Purple Crayon Players (2010 Recipient of Outstanding New Children's Theatre Company Award), Producer (multiple student productions)
- Courses included Accounting and Business Finance, Web Design, Theatre Production

#### PROJECTS

### Podcaster, "Here There Be Dragons"

 Started a weekly podcast discussing the TV show Black Sails. Designed the artwork, found a theme song, produced recording sessions, edited all episodes, wrote listing copy, uploaded to RSS feeds and promoted on social media.

#### Theatrical Producer

- Produced several theatrical events including three plays in Chicago and one in NYC. Managed the budgets, hired artists and business staff, fundraised, marketed, created production schedules and performed other logistical tasks such as negotiating with venues for rehearsal and performance spaces.
- One of the plays, PINK MILK, received ★★★★ from a Chicago Tribune review and was nominated for four regional awards.

#### - ADDITIONAL SKILLS

#### Digital Marketing

Google AdWords,
Facebook/Instagram
Advertising, Snapchat,
YouTube, DoubleClick for
Advertisers

#### **Productivity**

Excel, Word, Powerpoint, Apple Pages, Keynote, Numbers. Google: Docs, Sheets, Slides. Basecamp, Slack, Trello, Notion

#### Creative

PhotoShop, GarageBand, Final Cut Pro. Basic HTML, CSS, Javascript and Unity

# **Louis Schermerhorn**

908 377 3862 in louis-schermerhorn louis.schermerhorn@gmail.com